Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about something that is, well, not so fun
我是Catherine，今天我们聊的话题，嗯，可不太愉快。
when it happens.
当它发生的时候。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about those situations where people are trying to take advantage
今天我们要聊聊那些别人想占我们便宜的情况。
of us.
占我们便宜。
All right.
好的。
They're lying to us so they can take our money.
他们对我们撒谎，好骗走我们的钱。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and when we come back in a moment, we'll be talking
我们来听听今天的对话，稍后回来时，我们会聊聊你即将听到的一些单词和短语。
about some of these words and phrases that you're about to hear.
I got an urgent email from Tom.
我收到汤姆发来的一封紧急邮件。
He says he's in London and got robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel.
他说他在伦敦被抢了，需要我们给他电汇一些钱付酒店费用。
What?
什么？
That sounds really dodgy to me.
我觉得这听起来很可疑。
No way.
不可能。
Tom is an honest person.
汤姆是个诚实的人。
He wouldn't lie to me.
他不会对我撒谎。
No, I mean, it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent that out.
不，我是说，好像有人黑了他的邮箱账户，发了那封邮件。
I mean, think about it.
我是说，你想想看。
Why would he email you instead of calling you?
他为什么不打电话给你，而要发邮件呢？
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money?
你真的觉得有人想骗人寄钱吗？
For sure.
当然。
There's so many con artists out there.
外面骗子太多了。
You never really know.
你永远搞不清楚。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So let's take a look at some language on Language Takeaway.
那我们来“语言小贴士”环节看看一些语言点。
In Language Takeaway, Marco, one of the first things we hear is that I got an urgent email
在“语言小贴士”里，Marco，我们听到的第一件事是“我收到汤姆发来的一封紧急邮件”。
from Tom.
没错。
That's right.
所以这是一个形容词，表示紧急的东西。
So this is an adjective, something that is urgent.
它是紧急的。
It's urgent.
意思是需要立刻处理。
It means it needs to be looked at immediately.
非常重要。
It's very important.
没错。
That's right.
所以你可以有一封紧急邮件。
So you can have an urgent email.
意思是一封非常重要的邮件，或者某种情况可能是紧急的。
That means it's a very important email or something in a situation can be urgent.
对，就像紧急情况。
Yeah, like an emergency.
所以是紧急护理。
So urgent care.
我们在医院里会说到。
We talk about at the hospital.
就是需要医生立刻、紧急处理的事情。
It's something that needs to be looked at by a doctor immediately, urgently.
没错。
That's right.
紧急地。
Urgently.
那是副词形式。
That would be the adverb.
然后我们接着说，这封邮件很紧急，因为是汤姆发来的，邮件里说他在伦敦被抢了。
So we go on to say that the email is urgent because it's from Tom and the email said that
he is in London and he got robbed.
好的，他被抢了。
All right, he got robbed.
好的。
All right.
所以“抢劫”是动词，R-O-B，但这里重要的是看动词“got”。
So to rob is the verb, R-O-B, but here it's important to look at the verb got.
这意味着无论发生什么，都是发生在他身上，也就是这个朋友，被别人抢了。
This means that whatever's happening, it happened to him, to the friend by someone else.
没错。
That's right.
所以有人抢了他。
So someone robbed him.
好的，他被抢了。
All right, he got robbed.
意思是有人拿走了他的钱，对吧？
That means someone took his money, right?
没错。
That's right.
所以动词是“get”，而“robbed”是形容词，以ed结尾，但我们也有动词“rob”，如果你抢劫某人，意思是你偷了他的钱。
So the verb would be to get and robbed would be an adjective ending ed, but we also have
the verb to rob and if you rob someone, that means that you are stealing his or her money.
对，如果我抢了Marco，意思是我从他那里拿走了钱，但如果我被Marco抢了，意思是他拿走了我的钱。
Yeah, if I rob Marco, it means I take Marco's money from him, but if I got robbed by Marco,
it means he took my money.
没错。
That's right.
所以如果你单独用动词“rob”，意思是你正在做这个动作，或者有人正在偷另一个人的东西，但如果你“get robbed”或一个人“got robbed”，意思是他或她的钱被拿走了。
So if you use the verb to rob by itself, that means that you are doing the action or someone
is stealing from another person, but if you get robbed or a person got robbed, that means
现在这个朋友被抢了，有人拿走了他的钱，我们被要求给他电汇一些钱。
he or her got money taken from him.
Now the friend got robbed, someone took his money and we've been asked to wire him some
好的，电汇钱。
money.
没错，电汇钱。
Okay, to wire money.
这基本上就是寄钱的意思。
That's right, to wire money.
这是一种非常古老的寄钱方式。
This basically means to send money.
基本上你是通过电子方式寄钱。
It's a very old way or form of sending money.
你不是真的买个信封，放些钱进去，然后邮寄。
Basically you're sending money electronically.
你去银行或西联汇款，通过电子方式转账。
You don't actually buy an envelope and put some money in it and send it in the mail.
没错。
You go to a bank or Western Union and you transfer the money electronically.
所以发送电子转账，我们通常说“wire someone some money”。
That's right.
对，我会电汇给你。
So to send an electronic transfer of money, we usually say you wire someone some money.
没错。
Yeah, I'll wire it to you.
好的。
That's right.
所以今天课程的主题是关于人们试图诈骗其他人。
All right.
好的，这里的动词“scam”意思是撒谎或对某人不诚实，以便拿走他们的钱或占他们便宜。
So the main topic about today's lesson is about people trying to scam other people.
所以今天课程的主题是关于人们试图诈骗其他人。
All right, here the verb to scam means to lie or to be dishonest with someone so that
好的，这里的动词“scam”意思是撒谎或对某人不诚实，以便拿走他们的钱或占他们便宜。
you can take their money or to take advantage of them.
That's right.
没错。
So to scam means to take advantage of someone, to lie to someone, but you also have a scam,
所以，“scam”意思是利用某人、对某人撒谎，但“scam”也可以作名词，
a noun, which is a situation where people are trying to take your money.
指一种试图骗走你钱的情况。
So a very famous scam might be people in a big city like Paris saying, Oh, I'm a tourist.
一个很有名的骗局可能是，在巴黎这样的大城市里，有人说：“哦，我是个游客。”
I'm lost.
“我迷路了。”
Can you help me?
“你能帮我吗？”
Can you give me some money to go to the train station?
“你能给我点钱去火车站吗？”
And really these people, they're not lost.
实际上这些人并不迷路。
They just want you to give them money.
他们只是想让你给他们钱。
That's right.
没错。
This is called a scam.
这就叫骗局。
And what they're doing is they are trying to scam you.
而他们正在做的就是试图骗你。
That's right.
没错。
And so we actually have a word for these type of people.
所以我们确实有一个词来形容这类人。
We say they are con artists.
我们说他们是“骗子艺术家”。
They are conning you.
他们在骗你。
A con artist.
一个骗子艺术家。
Okay.
好的。
So we know what an artist is.
所以我们知道什么是艺术家。
An artist is a person who maybe paints pictures or makes something creative.
艺术家是可能画画或创作一些有创意东西的人。
But a con is someone who breaks the law.
但骗子就是违法的人。
So a con artist is someone who creatively breaks the law.
所以骗子艺术家就是创造性地违法的人。
That's right.
没错。
So these are basically thieves or people who take advantage of other people or steal from
所以这些人基本上就是小偷，或者以非常有创意的方式利用他人、从他人那里偷东西的人。
other people in a very creative way.
从他人那里偷东西的人。
So there are situations where they may sell something that doesn't even really belong
所以有些情况下，他们可能会卖掉甚至不属于他们的东西。
to them.
不属于他们的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So the thing to remember here with a con artist is that there's almost always a story.
所以这里要记住，骗子艺术家几乎总是会编一个故事。
You know, you have to, they give you this story and they make you believe them and then
你知道，他们得给你讲这个故事，让你相信他们，然后
you give them money or you give them some help that they don't deserve and that way
你就给他们钱，或者给他们一些他们不配得到的帮助，这样
they take it away from you.
他们就从你这里拿走了。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好了。
So we've taken a look at a lot of language here.
我们这里看了很多语言点。
Let's take a break, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们休息一下，再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
I got an urgent email from Tom.
我收到汤姆的一封紧急邮件。
He says he's in London and got robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel.
他说他在伦敦被抢了，需要我们给他汇点钱付酒店费。
What?
什么？
That sounds really dodgy to me.
我觉得这听起来很可疑。
No way.
不可能。
Tom is an honest person.
汤姆是个诚实的人。
He wouldn't lie to me.
他不会骗我的。
No, I mean, it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent that out.
不，我是说，好像有人黑了他的邮箱，发了那封邮件。
I mean, think about it.
你想想看。
Why would he email you instead of calling you?
他为什么不打电话给你，而要发邮件呢？
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money?
你真的觉得有人想骗人寄钱吗？
For sure.
当然。
There's so many con artists out there.
外面骗子太多了。
You never really know.
你永远搞不清楚。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Let's take a look at four key phrases on Fluency Builder.
我们来看看流利度训练中的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So we've got two friends who are talking.
我们有两个朋友在聊天。
One friend says that they got an urgent email from Tom and the other says, wow, that sounds
一个朋友说他们收到了汤姆的一封紧急邮件，另一个说，哇，这听起来
really dodgy to me.
真的很可疑。
Just right.
没错。
So if something sounds dodgy or something is dodgy, it means it doesn't really sound
所以如果某事听起来可疑或某事可疑，意思是它听起来不太
believable or correct or legal.
可信、正确或合法。
That's right.
对。
So maybe I can't trust it.
所以也许我不能信任它。
Something is dodgy if it doesn't sound like something I would want to trust.
如果某件事听起来不像我愿意信任的，那它就有问题。
And I think you can say it about a situation.
而且我觉得你可以用它来形容一个情况。
So this robbery, it sounds quite dodgy.
所以这起抢劫案听起来相当可疑。
You can also say it about food, right?
你也可以用它来形容食物，对吧？
Right.
对。
So if something looks kind of dodgy, it means it doesn't really look safe.
所以如果某样东西看起来有点可疑，那就意味着它看起来不太安全。
Yeah.
是的。
Maybe I'll be sick if I eat it.
也许我吃了会生病。
So it's quite dodgy looking.
所以它看起来相当可疑。
Right.
对。
Or even a person can look dodgy.
甚至一个人也可以看起来可疑。
So maybe that person is not really someone you want to trust.
所以那个人可能不是你真正想信任的人。
A con artist doesn't always look dodgy.
骗子并不总是看起来可疑。
But if a person looks dodgy and they ask you for money, probably shouldn't give it that
但如果一个人看起来可疑，还向你要钱，大概不应该给他。
many money.
很多钱。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
So that's dodgy.
所以这就是“dodgy”的意思。
Now, the person answers by saying, no way.
现在，对方回答说：“不可能。”
Tom is an honest person.
汤姆是个诚实的人。
He wouldn't lie to me.
他不会对我撒谎。
He's not dodgy.
他不狡猾。
He's not.
他不是那样的人。
No way.
不可能。
Right.
对。
Now, this is a really popular thing to say.
现在，这是一个非常流行的说法。
And it means basically, that's not possible.
它的基本意思是“那不可能”。
I don't agree with you.
我不同意你的看法。
I disagree.
我不同意。
And it's pretty forceful, actually.
而且实际上，它相当有力。
You're expressing your opinion.
你在表达你的观点。
So if I say, the Chicago White Sox are the best baseball team in the world.
所以如果我说：“芝加哥白袜队是世界上最好的棒球队。”
No way.
不可能。
No, you're wrong.
不，你错了。
I think the Yankees are the best.
我认为洋基队是最好的。
We could go back and forth.
我们可以来回争论。
No way.
不可能。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
But basically, you're disagreeing.
但基本上，你是在表示不同意。
That's right.
没错。
Now, the situation evolves around the fact that someone may have hacked Tom's email account
现在，这个情况围绕着一个事实：可能有人黑了汤姆的电子邮件账户，
and send out that email.
并发送了那封邮件。
All right.
好的。
So the phrase here would be to hack an account or to hack a website.
所以这里的短语是“黑进账户”或“黑进网站”。
It's important to remember that the verb to hack is pretty recent.
重要的是要记住，“hack”这个动词是相当新的。
We talk mostly about computers and the internet when we talk about hacking.
当我们谈论黑客行为时，主要涉及电脑和互联网。
Right.
对。
And it means to gain access, all right, to go into somebody's account without permission.
它的意思是未经许可进入某人的账户。
Right.
对。
It can be illegally or, like you said, without permission.
这可能是非法的，或者像你说的，未经许可。
So if your email account gets hacked, it means someone else accessed it without your permission
所以如果你的电子邮件账户被黑了，就意味着别人未经你允许
or illegally.
或非法地访问了它。
So when someone has access to your account, they hack it.
所以当有人访问你的账户时，他们就黑了它。
Usually they send out an email with your name.
通常他们会以你的名义发送一封邮件。
So your friends think it's you, but really it's someone who is maybe a con artist or
所以你的朋友以为是你，但实际上可能是个骗子或
someone who's not trustworthy.
不可信的人。
That's right.
没错。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
So that's the word to hack or maybe the noun, the person that hacks is called a hacker.
所以这就是“hack”这个词，或者名词形式，做黑客的人叫“hacker”。
Now moving on to our last phrase.
现在继续讲我们最后一个短语。
When we agree with someone forcefully, like we said, no way was to disagree.
当我们强烈同意某人时，就像我们说的，“no way”表示不同意。
When we do agree, we say for sure.
当我们同意时，我们说“for sure”。
That's right.
没错。
This is basically the opposite.
这基本上是相反的。
In this situation, we were thinking, well, do you really think someone is trying to hack
在这种情况下，我们在想：你真的认为有人试图黑进
his account?
他的账户吗？
The answer was for sure.
回答是“for sure”。
That means definitely, absolutely.
那意思是“肯定地”、“绝对地”。
That's right.
没错。
For sure.
当然。
It's another way of agreeing, strongly agreeing with someone or with what someone said.
这是另一种表示同意的方式，强烈同意某人或某人说的话。
For sure.
当然。
All right.
好的。
So that's all we have for today.
这就是我们今天要讲的全部内容。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍对话。
I got an urgent email from Tom.
我收到汤姆的一封紧急邮件。
He says he's in London and got robbed and needs us to wire him some money for his hotel.
他说他在伦敦被抢了，需要我们给他汇点钱付酒店费。
What?
什么？
That sounds really dodgy to me.
这听起来很可疑。
No way.
不可能。
Tom is an honest person.
汤姆是个诚实的人。
He wouldn't lie to me.
他不会对我撒谎。
No, I mean, it seems like someone may have hacked his email account and sent that out.
不，我是说，好像有人黑了他的电子邮件账户，然后发了那封邮件。
I mean, think about it.
我是说，你想想看。
Why would he email you instead of calling you?
他为什么不打电话给你，而要发邮件呢？
Do you really think someone is trying to scam people into sending money?
你真的认为有人想骗人寄钱吗？
For sure.
当然。
There's so many con artists out there.
外面有那么多骗子。
You never really know.
你永远搞不清楚。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So talking about scams and con artists in China, there is actually a very, very, very
说到中国的骗局和骗子，其实有一个非常非常非常
famous scam involving tea.
有名的关于茶的骗局。
That's right.
没错。
And this is something that you might experience in Beijing or Shanghai or any big city.
这是你在北京、上海或任何大城市可能会遇到的事情。
I hope you don't.
我希望你不会遇到。
But basically, as a tourist, you're traveling around, you go to a major tourist site like
但基本上，作为一个游客，你四处旅行，去一个主要旅游景点，比如
Tiananmen or the People's Square in Shanghai and some other tourists, some Chinese tourists,
天安门或上海的人民广场，然后一些其他游客，一些中国游客，
they come to you and they say, hello, where are you from?
他们走到你面前说，你好，你从哪里来？
Are you traveling here?
你是来这里旅游的吗？
We're traveling too.
我们也在旅行。
And then after about half an hour, maybe one hour of talking, they say, hey, we were thinking
然后聊了大约半小时，也许一个小时，他们说，嘿，我们在想
about going to have some tea.
要不要去喝点茶。
There's a tea festival.
那里有个茶节。
Would you like to come with us?
你想跟我们一起去吗？
Right.
对。
And you go and you drink some tea and you chat and you think, wow, I've made some nice
然后你去了，喝了些茶，聊着天，心想，哇，我交到了几个不错的
new friends.
新朋友。
These people are very nice.
这些人很好。
And then you get the bill.
然后你拿到账单。
Right.
对。
And it's like 200 US dollars, which is pretty crazy for tea.
结果要200美元，这对茶来说太离谱了。
So exactly.
就是这样。
It's a scam.
这是个骗局。
These people are con artists.
这些人是骗子。
They build trust.
他们建立信任。
They make you trust them.
他们让你信任他们。
They make you think, wow, I have nice new friends.
他们让你觉得，哇，我有了不错的新朋友。
And then they steal your money.
然后他们偷你的钱。
They steal your money.
他们偷你的钱。
That's right.
没错。
It's a very popular scam in China.
这是中国很常见的一种骗局。
And basically, if you do come here, just be aware of it.
基本上，如果你来这里，只要注意一下就行。
It's usually young people.
通常是年轻人。
They say they're university students or they say they are from another city.
他们说自己是大学生，或者说来自另一个城市。
And like you say, they build trust.
就像你说的，他们建立信任。
They invite you to have tea.
他们邀请你去喝茶。
And you think, well, why not?
你会想，嗯，为什么不呢？
You know, to learn more about the culture, to learn more about the country you're visiting.
你知道，为了多了解文化，多了解你正在旅行的国家。
And they turn out to try to scam you.
结果他们是想骗你。
That's right.
没错。
And the most popular one is the artists.
最流行的一种是艺术家骗局。
I'm a local artist.
我是本地艺术家。
I would like to show you my newest work.
我想给你看看我的最新作品。
And then they take you and the work is very expensive and they make you buy it.
然后他们带你去，作品很贵，逼你买下来。
So just be aware.
所以要多加小心。
I think what you said is true, Marco, that you just have to be careful and have to recognize
我觉得你说得对，Marco，你只需要小心，并且要意识到
that not everyone wants to be your friend.
不是每个人都想成为你的朋友。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
So be careful when you're traveling.
所以旅行时要小心。
And I'm sure it happens in many other countries.
我相信很多其他国家也有这种事。
Maybe you have some stories that you've experienced or maybe some local types of scams that you
也许你有过一些经历，或者你知道你们国家的一些本地骗局，
may know about in your country.
可以分享一下。
That's right.
没错。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Try and use those new words, con artist and scam.
试着用用那些新词，con artist和scam。
We'll be around answering your questions.
我们会在这里回答你的问题。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
Transgotradia.com